RAHUL HIRANI

Frontend Developer

er.rahulhirani@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/rahulhirani24/ · github.com/arhirani +91-7999713892

Frontend Developer at Walmart Global Tech with 5+ years of experience in HTML/CSS, JavaScript and ReactJS. Adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction.

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- TypeScript

- ReactJS with Redux
- NodeJS with ExpressJS
- GraphQL with Apollo

EXPERIENCE

Walmart Global Tech, Bengaluru | Frontend Engineering Lead | June 2020 - Present

- Leading the Front-End Development team for Jasper An IoT Solution to manage assets and provide proper maintenance with features like Asset telemetry, Work Order Management, Alert Detection and Diagnostics, as a part of which I built 3 applications from scratch.
- Led the migration of the applications from Monolith to MicroFrontEnd.
- Owned the stages from development to deployment of the UI Feature Development, CICD, Quality checks.

Tricog Health Services, Bengaluru | Full Stack Developer | Jan 2020 – May 2020

- Developed a Single Page Application for doctors to help them view and diagnose ECG, Treadmill and Spirometry reports of a patient so as to detect the cardiac arrest warning signs.
- Worked closely with the business team to understand the requirements better and deliver a superior end product.

Lowe's, Bengaluru | Frontend Developer | October 2017 – Jan 2020

- Worked on the design and development of Cart and Checkout for lowes.com.
- Architected Web and API frameworks with NodeJS and HapiJS.

Wipro Technologies, Hyderabad | Frontend Developer | Dec. 2016 – Sept. 2017

- Enhanced the existing Tyre Processing System application for Michelin (client) and maintained a 95% satisfaction score.
- Collaborated closely with designers to achieve high usability scores.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Book Search Engine

A Full-Fledged Search Engine for Books where a user can search books based on summaries. https://github.com/arhirani/Book-Search-Engine

Calendar App

Full-Fledged calendar which also allows the user to set reminders https://github.com/arhirani/calendar-web-app

Project Management Tool

An SPA for adding projects, tasks and tracking their status. https://github.com/arhirani/Project-Management-App

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY, COMPUTER SCIENCE ITM UNIVERSITY, GWALIOR (2012 – 2016)

CGPA: 8.25/10

President of Programming Community

AWARDS AND ACCOLADES

2021 | Walmart Rookie of the Year | Walmart

2019 | Spot Award | Lowe's

2018 | Spot Award | Lowe's

2017 | Best Junior Developer | Wipro